杰布?
Jeb?
杰布，你在哪?
Jeb, where are you?
-你还好吗?-我没事。
- Are you all right? - I'm all right.
给你带了些东西，一些饭和豆子，还有一个不错的食堂。
Brought you some things, some meal and beans and a good canteen.
所以你才一直买那些东西吗?
Is that what kept you, getting those things?
我尽快赶来了，我还给你带了张地图，看。
Came as soon as I could, I brought you a map too, look.
你往北走，穿过格洛丽塔斯，就能到达皮肤之路。
You work up north through the Glorietas, you can hit the Skin road.
-我在北方工作?——是的,杰布。
- I work north? - Yes Jeb.
-你呢?你会在哪里?-我不跟你去
- What about you? Where will you be? - I'm not going with you.
你一进来我就知道了。
I knew it as soon as you came in.
看你脸上的表情和走路的样子。
By the look on your face and the way you walked.
你一直都是这样，能理解我的想法，感受我的感受。
You've always been like that, able to think with my thoughts and feel with my feelings.
但有件事把我们分开了。
But there's something that keeps us apart.
杰布，我们怎么了?为什么一切都出了问题?
Oh Jeb, what happened to us? Why did everything go wrong?
我不全知道，但我知道一些。
I don't know all of it but I know some.
我一直在想，这是开始的地方也是将要结束的地方。
I've been thinking and figuring, this is where started this is where is going to end.
看到上升了吗?我会过来的。
You see that rise? Be coming over that.
他会杀人。
He'll come killing.
-出来，否则我们会跟着你。-你听到了吗?
- Come out or we'll come in after you. - You hear it?
杰布，亲爱的，外面没人了。
Jeb honey, there's no one out there.
——你想象。-不是想象，是回忆。
- You're imagining. - Ain't imagining, remembering.
把发生的事情放在一起，我猜一定是发生了什么。
Putting together what happened, what I guess must've happened.
雷神，一切都回来了，强大而清晰，里面有答案。
Thor, it's all coming back, strong and clear, there's an answer in it.
我身上的某些东西解释了一切。
It's something about me that explains everything.
-杰布，我不明白-我会让你明白的。
- Jeb, I don't understand. - Going to make you understand.
我得赶在他们来之前。
I got to before they get here.
你知道我为什么来这里吗?
Do you know why I came to this place?
不，杰布，但那可不是个好藏身处。
No Jeb but it's not a good hideout.
他们肯定会跟踪你到这里。
They're sure to trail you here.
我来是为了另一个原因。很久以前，我来过这里。
I came for another reason. I was here before, long ago.
那时候还是个婴儿。
Was a baby then.
我被吓到了，只有孩子才会这样。
I was scared the way only a kid can get.
我在一个黑暗，寒冷的地方。
I was in a dark, cold place.
我闭上眼睛来摆脱噩梦。
I had my eyes closed to get away from some bad dreams.
我这辈子一直在做的梦，我一直不明白。
The same dream I've been having all my life, I've never understood it.
有靴子在跑，有闪光。
There were boots running, flashes.
爸爸?爸爸?但我父亲不在那里。
Daddy? Daddy? But my father wasn't there.
相反，一个陌生的女人躺在地板上，她爬向我。
Instead, a strange woman was lying on the floor, she crawled toward me.
那是我第一次见到你妈妈。
That was the first time I saw your mother.
儿子起床。不，杰布，你现在不能睡觉。
Get up son. No Jeb, you can't go to sleep now.
穿上衣服，儿子，我们要走了。
Get your clothes on son, we going away from here.
-那是谁?-那是杰布·兰德
- Who is that? - That's Jeb Rand.
现在，注意亚当和托尔。
Now, pay attention Adam and Thor.
这是杰布，他要和我们一起住。
This is Jeb, he's going to live with us.
来吧，帮帮你妹妹。
Come on now, help your sister.
他们走了，每个人都死了，他们都搬到别的地方去了。
They've gone, every danged one of them, they've moved away somewhere.
格兰特，如果你用那只手臂骑马你会失去它的。
Grant, if you ride with that arm you'll lose it.
就算到死我也要找到他们。
I'll find them if it takes me to the end of my life.
我躲起来或逃跑的想法从未完全消失。
The idea that I was hiding or running away never quite died out.
我想应该的，因为接下来的七年我没有躲起来。
Should've I guess, because the next seven years I wasn't hiding.
你妈妈一直在照顾我们而我和你还有亚当一起长大，上学，在我们搬去的新地方帮忙盖房子，把整个户外作为操场。
Your Ma was taking care of all of us and I was growing up with you and Adam, Going to school, helping to build a house in the new place we moved to, Having the whole outdoors for a playground.
直到我九岁或十岁的时候，我才开始做噩梦
I about stopped having nightmares until one day when I was about nine or ten-
看杰布一个黑人小妞我在房子下面找到的。
Look Jeb, a little black chick. I found under the house.
你怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
你知道怎么回事，你射伤了柯尔特手枪。
You know what's the matter, you shot the Colt.
拍摄柯尔特什么?你疯了吗?
Shot what Colt? You crazy?
妈妈。
Mom.
杰布停止,停止。
Jeb stop, stop.
妈妈，妈妈，他们又吵架了，妈妈。
Mom Mom, they're fighting again Mom.
别打了，孩子们，别打了。
Now, stop that fighting boys, stop that fighting.
别打了，别打了，孩子们。
Now stop it, stop that fighting boys.
托尔，打点水。
Thor, pump some water.
好了，停下，来吧，孩子们。好了，别打了，别打了。
Now, stop it, come on boys. Now, stop that fighting, come on, stop it.
亚当,杰布。
Adam, Jeb.
-这是怎么回事?-他开枪打了柯尔特。
- Now, what's it all about? - He shot the Colt.
-我没有。-你就是这么做的。
- I didn't. - You did so.
有人开枪打了我们的柯尔特?
Mean somebody shot our Colt?
说是他的，他说我不能骑。
Said it was his, he said I couldn't ride it.
但我还是骑了，他也可能是我。
But I rode it anyway, he took a shot at it or maybe me.
我不知道，但他杀了柯尔特。
I don't know but anyway he killed the Colt.
不，有人杀了他，但不是亚当。
No, somebody may have killed him but wasn't Adam.
他整个上午都在给马车加油。
He's been here all morning greasing the buckboard.
-有人朝你开枪?-会是谁呢，妈?
- Say somebody took a shot at you? - Who could it have been Ma?
嗯，我也不太清楚。
Well, I don't rightly know.
事实上，有几个猎鹿人在附近游荡。
Matter of fact, there were some deer hunters hanging around.
是的，长官，他们问我能不能找到我们的栅栏，我答应了。
Yes sir, they asked me if they could hunt down our fence and I told them yes.
你去把晚饭从炉子上拿下来，别再吵了。
You go and get your supper off the stove and no more fighting.
-你要去看那些人吗，妈?——这是正确的。
- You going to see those men Ma? - That's right.
你把轮子放回去。
You put that wheel back on.
-你找到我们了-你把你的踪迹掩盖得很好。
- So you found us. - You covered up your trail pretty well.
那孩子一告诉我有人想杀他，我就知道是你。
As soon as the boy told me somebody tried to kill him, I knew it was you.
格兰特，当律师对你的枪法没好处。
Being a lawyer hasn't done your shooting any good Grant.
是啊，也许几年前失去这个对谁都没好处。
Yeah, maybe losing this some years ago didn't help any either.
你欠我一辆柯尔特手枪。
You owe me for a Colt.
这该死的小东西太活泼了。当他爬走的时候，他破坏了我的目标。
Doggone critter was too lively. When he crawled off, he spoiled my aim.
你不能重来一次格兰特，我不会让你重来的。
You can't start it all over again Grant, I won't let you.
你现在有点自大了，不是吗?
Now you getting kind of uppity, ain't you?
他是兰德家的人，我第一眼看到他就知道了。
He's a Rand, I knew it the first minute I laid eyes on him.
他让我想起你嫁给了我哥哥。
He brought to mind that you was married to my brother.
他的死还没有了结。
And a score still isn't settled for his death.
你失去了哥哥，我失去了丈夫。我不想再为他报仇了。
You lost a brother, I lost a husband. I don't want any more vengeance for him.
我从没想过你会。所以我发誓要杀了世上所有的兰德人。
I never figured that you would. That's why I swore that I'd kill every Rand on earth.
他是唯一的幸存者。
And he's the only one left.
-你是怎么骂他的?-就算上帝把他给了我。
- How in tarnations you get him? - Let's say the lord gave him to me.
别管那孩子格兰特，他是无辜的。那晚结束了他的一切。
Let the boy alone Grant, he's innocent. That night ended it for him.
这样的夜晚是不会结束的。
A night like that don't have an end.
发生在他身上的事会让他做一些…就像鬼魂在他耳边说，杀，杀，你必须杀。
What happened to him there will make him do things just... just like spirits were whispering in his ear saying, kill, kill, you've got to kill.
鬼魂可能会跟你说话，但不会跟他说话，我不相信你的鬼魂。
Spirits may talk to you but they won't to him, I don't believe in your spirits.
也许不是，但总有一天你会希望我没有在今天的抽签中失手。
Maybe not but someday you'll wish I hadn't missed my shot today down on the draw.
这一天永远不会到来。他是个好孩子，我爱他就像爱自己的儿子一样。
That's one day that'll never come. He's a good boy, I love him like my own son.
你凭什么认为那个男孩爱你?
What makes you think that boy loves you?
我还是回圣达菲吧。
Well, I'll go back to Santa Fe.
我发誓我会放过兰德，让他长大，看看当他长大到开始问问题的时候你会怎么样。
I swear I think I'll leave that Rand alone, let him grow up, Just to see what happens to you when he's big enough to start asking questions.
别忘了带柯尔特手枪的钱。
Don't forget your money for the Colt.
谢谢你的提醒。
Thanks for reminding me.
能帮我把他养大。
Will help me bring him up.
你找到他们了吗，妈妈?你和他们谈过了吗?
Did you find them Ma? Did you talk to them?
我当然知道，是那些猎鹿人他们射杀了柯尔特。
Why sure I did, it was them deer hunters alright, they shot the Colt.
把亚当安置好，喂饱他们，你帮他，雷神。
Put the team up Adam and feed them, you help him Thor.
跟我回家吧，儿子，我想和你谈谈。
Come in the house with me son, I want to talk to you.
杰布你还记得跟我们一起住的事吗
Jeb, how much do you remember about coming to live with us.
关于我带你来的那晚?
About the night I brought you here?
-你一定记得什么。——不是。
- You must remember something. - Not much.
-你可以告诉我杰布-我一想到这个就搞混了。
- You can tell me Jeb. - I get mixed up when I think about that.
我记得闪光和靴子奔跑。
I remember flashes and boots running.
你知道你父母都死了，所以我才收留你。
You know your parents are dead, that's why I took you in.
是的,女士。
Yes ma'am.
-但你不记得了?——没有女士。
- But you don't remember them? - No ma'am.
有时候我试着去想，我不知道。
Sometimes I try to think about it, I don't know.
我的头受伤了。
My head hurts.
得到所有模糊。
Gets all blurred.
有时上帝通过只让我们知道需要做什么来保护我们。
Sometimes the lord protects us by letting us know only what's needful.
你不记得的事并不重要。
What you don't remember doesn't matter.
你现在属于我们了。
You belong here with us now.
不要问过去的问题，过去没有答案。
Don't ask questions of the past, it has no answers for you.
在给你的爱中坚强地成长。
Grow up strong in the love that's here for you.
只要你用爱来回报，什么都不会发生。
As long as you love in return, nothing can happen.
你是爱我们的，对吧，杰布?
And you do love us, don't you Jeb?
对不起，是我挑起的争吵。
I'm sorry I started the fight.
好了，孩子，今天以后你们就没有什么可吵的了。
Well son, after today you boys won't have anything to fight about.
亚当，托尔，过来。
Adam, Thor, come here.
现在，听我说，孩子们。
Now, pay heed to me you children.
我不想再和你争论这个牧场上谁拥有什么，小马还是别的什么。
I'll have no more arguments as to who owns what on this ranch, colts or anything else.
我们现在拥有的和将来会拥有的一切从今天开始都属于你们三个。
Everything we have or ever will have belongs to you three from this day on.
-你是说，一切都得这样?——是的亚当。
- You mean, everything has to be that way? - Yes Adam.
你对此有异议吗?-不是为了雷神和我，而是为了外人。
- Have you any objection to that? - Not for Thor and me but I've for outsiders.
这里没有外人。
There are no outsiders here.
你们三个在一起，你们是世上最美好的东西……一个家庭。
You three are together, you yourselves are the best and finest thing there is... a family.
你保证不会忘记吗?
You promise not to forget that?
我是说你们三个。
I mean all three of you.
好吧。
Alright.
托尔，别挠了，进屋去拿点煤油，敷在恙虫身上。
Thor, stop scratching, go in the house and get some coal oil, put it on those chiggers.
亚当，你去找剪羊的剪刀，我今晚给你和杰布剪头发。
Adam, you find the sheep scissors, I'm going to cut yours and Jeb's hair tonight.
杰布，我们一直叫你兰德。
Jeb, we've always called you by your right name Rand.
你想用我们的名字代替吗?
Would you like to use our name instead?
如果你不介意，我想用我自己的名字，杰布·兰德。
If you don't mind, I'd like to use my own name, Jeb Rand.
好杰布。
Alright Jeb.
你知道那之后的情况。马的想法就像她想要的那样，非常接近。
You know how it was after that. Ma's idea worked like she wanted it, pretty near.
不管怎样，我们看起来更像一家人，我们四个人很亲近。
Anyhow, we seemed more like a family, we were close, the four of us.
这种情况持续了很长一段时间，一直持续到我骑马进城的那天。
That lasted for a long time, it lasted until that day I rode into town.
细节停顿，右脸。
Detail halt, right face.
关于脸，命令，武器。
About face order arms.
你们吵吵闹闹是怎么回事?
What's all the shouting and drum beating about?
你没听到吗?该地区正在与西班牙作战。
Ain't you heard? The territory is fighting Spain.
看起来我们还会有一场真正的枪战。
And it looks like we're going to have a real shooting war too.
——嗨,杰布。-早上好，医生。
- Hi Jeb. - Good morning doctor.
你好，普伦蒂斯，你在这里可真热闹。
Hello Prentice, quite some excitement you got around here.
当然，得打败那些西班牙人。
Sure is, got to beat them Spaniards.
我当然希望我能打架，但爸爸不让。
Sure wish I could fight but dad won't let me.
意思是我不会谎报他的年龄让他加入。
Meaning I won't lie about his age so he can join.
我参加过一场战争，他都不知道自己在回避什么。
I fought in one war, he don't know what he's staying out of.
-这是你的信，杰布——谢谢Bam。
- Here's your mail Jeb. - Thanks Bam.
托尔要的裙子和衬裙进来了。
That dress and petticoat Thor sent for came in.
希望这是她想要的。我一直留着给她。
Hope it's what she wanted. I've been keeping it for her.
她很感激你，我告诉她我见过你。
She be obliged to you, I tell her I saw you.
我的信用怎么样巴姆?我需要一些烟草。
How's my credit Bam? I need some tobacco.
没听说卡勒姆农场的信用有什么问题。
Never heard anything wrong with the credit on the Callum ranch.
谢谢。
Thanks.
——兰德先生吗?——是的。
- Mr. Rand? - Yes.
我听到他提到卡勒姆农场。
I heard him mention the Callum ranch.
我是州立教务长，来这里监督招募。
I'm state provost, down here to supervise recruiting.
这里的每个机构都有配额。
Every outfit around about here is sending in a, a quota.
一个人一个人去打西班牙人。
One man a piece to fight the Spaniards.
我想看看有没有人从你的农场来。
I was sort of interested to see if anyone was coming in from your ranch.
我猜这就是你的意思先生，来晚了一点。
Oh, I guess this is what you mean sir, came a little late.
有些部队把他们所有的危险骑手都送来了。
Some of the outfits are sending in every danged rider they've got.
除了年老和不健康的人。
Except the aged and unfit.
哦，我们明天会告诉你是哪一个……我还是我弟弟亚当，够快了吗?
Oh, we'll let you know tomorrow which one it's going to be... me or my brother Adam, is that soon enough?
我想是的，除非你想…今晚骑马回家，告诉大家你刚刚加入了。
I guess so, unless you'd like the pleasure of... riding home tonight and telling the folks you've just joined up.
填好这张表，签上名，报告的时候交上来。
Fill this out and sign it, hand it in when you report.
如果报告的人是我，如果不是亚当就得去做。
If I'm the one that reports, if not Adam will have to do it.
给我两个。
Give me two.
教务长似乎下定决心要让你们卷入这场战争。
The provost seems bound and determined to get you into this war.
对我来说也是这样。
Sort of appeared that way to me too.
那家伙到底是谁?他叫什么名字?
Who is that fella anyway? What's his name?
见鬼，我以为你认识他。
Heck, I figured you knew him.
他不是你的亲戚吗?
Ain't he some kind of kin of yours?
-我没有亲戚，我没有亲戚。-他叫卡莱姆，一模一样
- No kin of mine, I have no kin. - His name is Callum, just the same.
在北边有很多这样的人。
There's a whole slew of them up north.
停止顺序。
Halt order arms.
新兵们已经准备好宣誓就职了，对吗，孩子们?
The recruits are ready to be sworn in, is that right boys?
好吧。举起你的右手。
Alright. Raise your right hands.
跟着我。
Repeat after me.
我，美国公民，庄严宣誓…我，美国公民，庄严宣誓…我将真诚地效忠于美利坚合众国。
I, a citizen of the United States, do solemnly swear... I, a citizen of the United States, do solemnly swear... That I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America.
我将真诚地效忠于美利坚合众国。
That I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America.
-是我的包裹吗?-是的，你订的干货。
- Is that package for me? - Yes, the dry goods you ordered.
太好了，可能是我的裙子。
Oh good, maybe it's my dress.
——嘿,亚当?——你好吗?
- Hey Adam? - Hello?
等你搞定了，就回屋子里来…-我有些事情要和你商量。——好的。
When you finish up there, come on in the house... - I got some business to talk over with you. - Alright.
它是什么?
What is it?
作为一名志愿军士兵，在美利坚合众国服役两年，除非提前退伍。
As a soldier in the volunteer army, of the United States of America... for a period of two years, unless sooner discharged.
第一个连队明早就要出发了。我跟他说到时候会告诉他的。
The first company is leaving in the morning. I told him we'd let him know by then.
这不公平，他们为什么不能从有很多骑手的大牧场调来士兵呢?
It's not fair, why can't they get soldiers from the big ranches... where there have plenty of riders?
没办法，姐姐，必须打败那些西班牙人。
Can't be helped Sis, them Spaniards has to be beat.
我不会放你们走的，我会骑马进城跟你们解释我们需要你们两个都在这里。
I won't let either of you go, I'll ride into town and explain we need both of you here.
你知道吗，你只能留一个在家，姐姐。
You know, you can only keep one of us at home Sis.
但是你可以帮助选择它是哪一个。
But you can help pick which one it's going to be.
-那是我不想要的工作。-我们应该告诉妈妈还是自己决定?
- That's a job I don't want. - Should we tell Ma or decide without her?
我说，我们自己决定，之后再告诉她。
Decide for ourselves, I say and tell her after.
好吧，Ad，你觉得怎么样?我们怎么解决?
Well Ad, what do you say? How we going to settle?
我同意你的任何建议。
I'm agreeable to anything you suggest.
好吧，我跟你一起抽号码，跟你赛跑或者抽牌。
Alright, I'll draw numbers with you, run you a race or cut cards.
这是你决定的方式，这不是游戏，这是严肃的。
That would be your way of deciding, this isn't a game, it's serious.
我是认真的。掷硬币怎么样?这是最快的。
I'm serious. How about a toss? That's the quickest.
-我没意见。-那就让我扔吧。
- That's fine with me. - Then let me toss it.
高抛。
Flip it high.
如果是反面，Ad就走。头,杰布。
If it's tails, Ad goes. Heads, it's Jeb.
它的脑袋。杰布，你是我的真命天子。
It's heads. Jeb, you're the one.
-这是个公平的选择。-就这样吧。
- It was a fair toss. - So be it.
好吧，再拖下去也没用了。
Well, there's no use stalling around any longer.
-亚当，你能帮我剪一匹马吗?——确定。
- Adam, will you cut out a horse for me? - Sure.
我今晚就走。最好现在就去告诉妈妈。
I'll get going tonight. Better go to Ma now and tell her.
别让你出事，杰布。
Don't let anything happen to you Jeb.
我受不了，如果你出了什么事-不会有事的，妈妈，我会回来的。
I couldn't stand that, if anything happened to you- Nothing is going to happen Ma, I'll come back.
当然，我知道你会的。你们其中一个必须离开。
Why sure, I know you will. One of you had to go.
也许这样是最好的。
Perhaps it's best this way.
再见杰布。
Good bye Jeb.
再见。
Good bye Ma.
-再见杰布——再见
- Good bye Jeb. - So long.
杰布回家。
Come home Jeb.
在那之前，也许你会喜欢这个作纪念。
Until I do, maybe you'd like this for a keepsake.
我猜它从你手里滑出去了，也从窗户滑出去了。
I guess it sort of slipped out of your hand, right through the window too.
它没有滑倒，是我扔的。
It didn't slip, I threw it.
我不怪你，你想把亚当留在这里所以你对投掷的事撒谎了。
I don't blame you, you want to keep Adam here so you lied about the toss.
我想撒谎，但我没有，如果我……会把你留在这里，而不是亚当
I wanted to lie but I didn't, if I had... would've been to keep you here, not Adam.
你也这么觉得吗?和我的感觉一样。
You felt that way too? The same way I felt.
我本该是你的妹妹。
I was supposed to be your sister.
我们还是孩子的时候就这样了。
It's how it's been ever since we were kids.
只是我不再是你的妹妹，你也不再是我的哥哥。
Only I stopped being your sister, and you've never been my brother.
但我不得不每天假装，整天看着你，让你抚摸我，晚上回到我的房间，躺在那里，想着你。
But I had to go on every day pretending, Watching you all day, letting you touch me, And at night going in my room, lay there, thinking about you.
我希望我撒了谎，我希望我在折腾的事上撒了谎，把你留在这里。
I wish I had lied, I wish I'd cheated about the toss and kept you here.
-等等我。-你知道我会的
- Wait for me. - You know I will.
我把他留在艾斯高车行，你明早再来接他。
I'll leave him at the Ace High livery stable, you can pick him up in the morning.
-再见，替我跟西班牙人打个招呼。-我会的。
- So long, give them Spaniards heck for me. - I'll do that.
来吧。
Come on.
-感觉好点了吗?-我感觉很好。
- Feel any better? - I feel all right.
我不知道你是否幸运，你肯定梦想着什么。
Well, I don't know whether you were lucky or not, you were sure dreaming of something.
我听过很多关于发烧的传言。
I've heard a lot of fever chatter in my time.
当涉及到战争的时候，不要太在意，你的不一样。
Don't bother with it much when it's concerned with war, yours was different.
好像是从你小时候的某个地方来的。
Seem to come from way back somewhere, when you were a kid.
-我说什么?-说什么靴子和闪光什么的。
- What I say? - Something about boots and flashes of light.
有人受伤或死亡。
Somebody hurt or killed.
-这对你有什么意义吗?-我不知道。
- Is that mean anything to you? - I don't know.
你得告诉我我说了什么，医生，每个字我都要知道。
You got to tell me what I said doc, every word, I want to know.
不要沮丧，你的高烧已经退了，噩梦也随之而来，不管它们从哪里来。
Don't upset yourself... your fever is gone and the nightmare is with it, wherever they came from.
-腿会送你回家的——回家吗?
- Leg is going to get you home. - Home?
舞台开始了。
The stage is in.
不,不。教务长想付钱。
No, no. The provost wants to pay for it.
谢谢你的款待，先生。
Oh, thank you sir, for the treat.
很高兴能招待一个对今天的场合不感兴趣的人。
It's a pleasure to treat a man who takes so little interest in today's occasion.
就我个人而言，我对一个该死的英雄也没什么兴趣。
See, personally I too have small interests in a doggone hero.
我们很欣赏杰布在牧场的表现。
We think a great deal of Jeb out at the ranch.
可惜他们没有铜管乐队来做牲畜统计。
Too bad they don't have a brass band for a good cattle tally.
我知道你在外面做得很好。
Understand you've been doing a fine job out there.
我不知道你的名字，先生。
I don't believe I know your name sir.
和你的一样，卡莱姆，我是圣达菲的检察官。
It's the same as yours, Callum, I'm the prosecutor at Santa Fe.
-我们是亲戚，你知道的-很高兴认识你。
- We're kin, you know. - Glad to make your acquaintance.
听。
Listen to that.
女士们不赞成杀戮，但她们是多么崇拜战争英雄。
The ladies deprecate killing but my, how they admire a war hero.
杰布的直觉很自然
Jeb you know, comes by his instincts naturally.
-他继承的。-是吗?
- He inherited them. - Is that so?
我还没跟认识杰布·兰德亲属的人说过话。
I don't believe I ever talked to anyone who knew Jeb Rand's kinfolk.
有时候，你可以自己去格洛里塔镇骑一骑……看看档案里关于一个叫兰德的家族有什么记录
Sometime, take a little ride for yourself up into Glorieta township... and see what the records have to say about a family named Rand.
祝你好运。
Good luck.
鉴于你的杰出表现，我现在授予你美利坚合众国的荣誉勋章。
For this meritorious and exceptional action, I now award you the medal of honor... of the United States of America.
很高兴见到你，妈妈。天啊，你看起来很好。
Good to see you Ma. My, you looking fine.
——你好,托尔。——你好,杰布。
- Hello Thor. - Hello Jeb.
-欢迎回家，杰布-谢谢你，亚当。
- Welcome home Jeb. - Thank you Adam.
很高兴回家了。
Glad to be home.
来吧，跟我一起过来。我们去牧场吧。
Come on, ride up here with me. Let's get on out to the ranch.
一旦你睡在自己的床上，吃在自己的桌子上，杰布…也许你已经忘记了将军说过的那些杀戮和枪击事件。
Once you sleeping in your own bed and eating at your own table Jeb... maybe you forget all about the killing and shooting the general talked so much about.
别忘了，妈，别再想了。
Don't have to forget it Ma, never think about it.
我本想留着感恩节吃的。
I was saving this for Thanksgiving.
反正我们也要过感恩节了。
I guess we're having a kind of Thanksgiving anyway.
-欢迎来到我儿子杰布身边-谢谢你，妈妈。
- Welcome to my son Jeb. - Thank you Ma.
敬你杰布，敬我一杯。
To you Jeb and you must drink to me.
来点音乐会很合适。
It would be fitting to have some music.
还记得男孩吗?伦敦德里的空气。
Remember boys? Londonderry Air.
为什么，你以前唱过。
Why, you used to sing it.
再一次，我将醒来……你沉睡时的甜蜜。
Once more, I'll awaken... The sweetness of thy slumbering strain.
我们含泪告别。
In tears our last farewell was taken.
现在我们又在泪水中重逢。
And now in tears we meet all again.
然而，即使那时和平在歌唱……她那宁静的歌声传遍陆地和海洋。
Yet, even then while peace was singing... Her halcyon song o'er land and sea.
虽然给别人带来欢乐和希望。
Though joy and hope to others bring ye.
她只是给你带来新的眼泪。
She only brought new tears to thee.
是的，杰布，你会发现变化，而且是好的变化。
Yes, Jeb, you'll find changes and good ones too.
我们新开了四个区，是你所见过的最豪华的鞋店。
We got four new sections of the richest fillery you ever saw.
当你离开一段时间后，我想任何关于牛的话题都会有些无聊。
Guess any kind of cattle talk is kind of... bore some after you've been away from it for a while.
就像今天有人对我说的，他们不会为牧牛人演奏铜管乐队。
Like a fellow said to me today, they don't play brass bands for cattlemen.
说到牛，杰布，你有权看这份记录。
Speaking of cattle Jeb, you're entitled to read this tally.
你会发现所有的操作都写在这里，清晰合法。
You'll find all the operations in here written down, clear and legal.
我不需要看广告，我相信你的票数。
Oh, I don't have to read Ad, I can trust your tally.
好吧，它就在那儿等着你去看。我把你的那份都划掉了。
Well, it's there for you to see. I get your share all marked off.
我称之为兰德份额。
I call it the Rand share.
坐下，阿德，再来点咖啡好吗?
Sit down Ad, won't you have some more coffee?
不,谢谢。
No thanks.
今天是重要的一天，对我来说一天都一样。
Well, it's been a big day, one day is the same as another to me.
我要在日出时坐好马鞍。
I got to be in the saddle at sun-up.
-晚安，妈妈。晚安，儿子。
- Good night Ma. - Good night son.
——晚安。晚安，亚当。
- Good night. - Good night Adam.
我会把这些吃完的。
I'll finish up these.
——不,你……-你去吧。
- No, you... - You go along.
好吧，我太累了。
Well alright, I'm all tuckered out.
-晚安杰布-晚安，妈妈。
- Good night Jeb. - Good night Ma.
这些进城的旅行使我疲惫不堪。
All these trips to town tire me out.
杰布……
Jeb...
你知道吗?
You know something?
——什么?-月亮出来了。
- What? - There's a moon out.
等一下，我去拿披肩。
Wait I'll get my shawl.
杰布?
Jeb?
杰布，亲爱的，出什么事了?
Jeb sweetheart, is something wrong?
托尔，我们该走了。
Thor, we ought to go away.
——我们将。-我是说现在今晚。
- We will. - I mean right now Tonight.
我们套上一匹马，不要告诉任何人。
Let's hitch up a horse and not tell anyone.
我们叫醒镇上的牧师，让他为我们主持婚礼。
We wake up a preacher over in town and make him marry us.
-你知道我会嫁给你的-我们还等什么?
- You know I'll marry you. - What are we waiting for?
我要你来追求我。
I want you to come court me.
我知道这听起来很傻，因为我们是一起长大的，但是…我想假装我们没有。
I know that seems silly when we grew up together but... I want to pretend we didn't.
这就是为什么你要来激励我。
That's why you've got to come sparking me.
你介意吗?你可以把自己打扮得很时髦。
Do you mind? You can get dressed up real fashionable.
我也要，我要在走廊里放两把椅子。
So will I, I'll have two chairs out in the gallery.
我拿点柠檬水来，我们坐着聊聊。
I'll bring out some lemonade, we'll sit there and talk.
你可以问我能不能让你抽烟，我会答应的。
You can ask me if I'll let you smoke and I'll say yes.
-我来缝一段。-我们要谈什么?
- I'll have a piece of sewing. - What will we talk about?
哦，有点像会客室里的谈话。
Oh, sort of parlor talk.
这些话就像缝线一样，把我们的生活缝合在一起。
The words will be like stitches that sew and pull on our lives together.
过一会儿你就可以握住我的手了。
After a while you can hold my hand.
在你买戒指之前你是不应该吻我的。
You're not supposed to kiss me till you bought a ring.
杰布，你能理解吗?
Oh Jeb, can you understand?
你能从我的角度看出来吗?
Can you see it in my way?
托尔，我从来就不属于这里。
Thor, I've never belonged here.
不知道为什么，总有一种感觉，有什么东西在追我。
I don't know why, always have a feeling something is after me.
我无法解释这种糟糕的感觉。
It's a bad feeling I can't explain.
很多时候我很开心，但它仍然存在。
Lots of times I'm happy but it's still there.
托尔，我要和你在一起。
Thor, I've got to be with you.
我们得有个机会，在事情发生之前赶紧离开。请甜心。
We got to have a chance, let's get away before something happens. Please sweetheart.
我们要结婚了，杰布
We're going to get married Jeb.
我们不会因为觉得会发生什么事就把余生都花在做疯狂的事情上。
We're not going to spend the rest of our lives... doing crazy things because you think something is going to happen.
我们不会像两个公共马车劫匪一样在晚上逃跑。
We're not going to run away at night like a couple of stagecoach robbers.
我爱你，杰布。
I love you Jeb.
但如果我们要结婚，就不能按我说的那样吗?
But if we're going to get married, can't it be the way I say?
甜心吗?
Please sweetheart?
我只希望结果是那样。
I only hope it turns out that way.
在那之后，我必须独自一人把事情想清楚。
After that I had to be alone and think things out.
我们并没有吵过架，但不知怎么的我们吵过。
We hadn't really quarreled and yet somehow we had.
好像我们再也不能理解对方了。
It seemed as if we couldn't understand each other anymore.
有一天，我骑马去了巴特村。
One day, I rode up into Butte country.
直接来到这个地方，就好像我认识路一样。
Came straight to this place, just as if I'd known the way.
我生命中有一样东西像那栋房子一样被毁了。
There was something in my life as ruined as that house.
那房子就是我自己。
That house was myself.
我以前见过无数次了，壁炉……陷阱门。
I'd seen it a million times before, the fireplace... the trap door.
后面有一些牛骨头。
Out back there was some cattle bones.
然后当我在边上走的时候，我看到了一些没有标记的坟墓。
And then as I walked around the side I came on some unmarked graves.
我突然无法呼吸。
All the sudden I couldn't breathe.
如果那房子是我，我的哪一部分会埋在那些坟墓里?
If that house was me, what part of me was buried in those graves?
有些人有肉馅。
Some folks has meat beat.
当有工作要做的时候，他们就决定在这个时候骑马到乡下去。
When there's work to be done, that's the time they... decide to go riding all over the countryside.
亲爱的，我很担心你，我们不知道你在哪里。
Honey, I was worried about you, we didn't know where you were.
-不好意思，我只是随便逛了一下。-你多久没吃东西了?
- I'm sorry, I just took a little ride. - How long since you had something to eat?
-我不知道，但我不饿。-我给你倒杯咖啡。
- I don't know but I'm not hungry. - I'll fix you some coffee.
很好，现在我要见妈妈。
That'll be fine, right now I want to see Ma.
-你跟鸭子一样没脑子。-好吧，我很明智地回家了。
- You got no more sense than a duck. - Well, I had sense enough to come home.
托尔为你担心得要命。
Why, Thor was fit to be tied worrying over you.
我自己也有点担心，迷路了一半。
Was sort of worried myself, got a halfway lost.
我在临海岩的乡村迷路了，在熊爪堡的路上。
Strayed away up in that Rimrock country, up Bear Paw Butte way.
熊掌孤峰?是什么疯狂的事让你这么做的?
Bear Paw Butte? Now, what crazy thing made you do that?
-你和托尔亲热了?-我去跟托尔没关系
- You and Thor have a nip up? - Thor had nothing to do with my going.
我想问你点事，妈。
I want to ask you something Ma.
我一直在想那边的老农场。
I've been wondering about that old ranch up there.
山羊不能在那个范围内生存，小毛驴会饿死的。
A goat couldn't live in that range, a burro would starve.
人们曾经住在那里，你知道，我指的是牧场。
People lived there once though, you know, the ranch I mean.
我刚想起来，在我看来，很久以前那里有个地方。
I just remembered, seems to me there was, some place up there long ago.
在我看来，我以前去过那里。
Seems to me I've been there before.
玛·卡勒姆，那个农场跟我有关系吗?
Ma Callum, does that ranch have to do with me?
-别问我问题，杰布-我小时候也是从那里来的吗?
- Don't ask me questions Jeb. - Did I come from there as a boy?
那是你多年前带我去的地方吗?
Is that where you took me from all those years ago?
所以我才记得吗?
Is that why I remember it?
我告诉过你不要回头看。
I told you not to look backward.
——展望未来。-我听你的话，我按你说的生活。
- Look ahead. - I obeyed you, I've lived like you said.
我一直都知道我不属于这里。
All my life I've known I didn't really belong here.
我不能爱，我不能回报你的好意。
I couldn't love, I couldn't return your kindness.
我有什么问题吗?
Is there something the matter with me?
我想了解你，妈，你得告诉我。
I want to understand Ma, you got to tell me.
杰布，你没什么问题。
There's nothing the matter with you Jeb.
那个牧场对我来说可能比你更重要。不管怎样，一提起它我就心烦意乱。
That ranch might mean more to me than it does to you. Anyway, I get upset talking about it.
一个人必须找到他自己的答案。
A person is got to find his own answers.
我们每个人都是孤独的，而且以不同的方式。
We're alone, each of us, and each in a different way.
-我不会孤单的，我要嫁给雷神。-我希望你这么做。
- I won't be alone, I'm going to marry Thor. - I want you to.
但当你做到了，你就有了未来。
But when you do, you got the future to live for.
我也要面对过去。
Got the past to live with too.
-我的孩子们将不得不忍受。-别烦我了，杰布·兰德
- My children will have to live with it. - Stop vexing me Jeb Rand.
我要把我女儿送给你做你的妻子。
I'm giving you my daughter for your wife.
这还不够吗?这难道不表明你是被爱的吗?
Isn't that enough for you? Doesn't that show you that you're loved?
带着你的怀疑和你的…熊掌巴特还有你疯狂的长途骑行，别烦我了。
Go away from me with your doubts and your, your... Bear Paw Butte and your crazy long rides, leave off vexing me.
你曾经告诉过我不要问你问题，但问题总是回来。
You told me once not to question you, but the questions keep coming back.
如果你不回答我，我就得去别的地方找答案了。
If you won't answer me, I'll have to look somewhere else for the answer.
出去杰布?
Going out Jeb?
我想我该去看看丁格尔先生的法罗游戏是否还像以前那样狡猾。
Thought I'd go and see if Mr. Dingle's faro game is still as crooked as ever.
好主意。
Good idea.
-你说什么?-我说这是个好主意。
- What you say? - I said it was a good idea.
你想不想带上两三千块钱，跟你赌一把?
How you like to take two or three thousand dollars along, stake you in the game?
也许我们中有人疯了，但我好像不太懂你。
Maybe one of us is crazy, but I don't seem to follow you.
如果你肯花点时间看一看那本图册就简单多了。
Tally book would've made it kind of simple if you'd taken the trouble to read it.
所以你回家的时候我才把它给你。
That's why I gave it to you when you came home.
只是现在，我增加了今年的收成。
Only now, I got this year's crop added.
两三千镑也不过是你应得的那一份。
Two or three thousand would be no more than your share of the profits.
我们每人三分之一，老妈子想要的。
A third to each of us, Way Ma wants it.
你太慷慨了，比我应得的还多，完全出乎我的意料。
It's mighty generous, more than I deserve, least way as expected.
谢谢，还有件事你不知道。
Thanks, here's something else you don't know.
你在部队的时候，我们一直在为你存钱。
All the time you were in the army, we've been banking money for you.
一千五百美元，只有一个问题杰布。
Fifteen hundred dollars, there's just one thing wrong with it Jeb.
那笔钱是从农场赚来的，不是你赚的。
That money came out of the ranch and you didn't earn it.
我一直在做我的那份工作，也在做你的那份工作，我不打算继续这样做。
I've been working my share and yours too, I don't aim to keep on doing that.
-我从没要求你这么做-不，但你也从没想过要帮我。
- I never asked you to. - No but you never tried to help me either.
你的脚已经好了一个月了，而你却躺在阴凉处领了那笔钱。
Your foot is been well for a month, and you've been drawing that money for... lying in the shade.
我很幸运没有六名骑手跟你一起玩投球。
I was lucky if I didn't have six of my riders stretched out alongside you playing pitch.
当然，我知道你曾经是个英雄，但我也受够了。
Oh sure, I know you were a hero once, but I've had my belly full of that too.
我们这里可没有奖牌。
We don't pay off in medals around here.
我回家就太糟糕了。
It was too bad I came home at all.
如果我没有，你就会拥有牧场和…塔利的钱，还有我的那份全部留给你。
If I hadn't, you would've had the ranch and the... tally money and my share of everything all to yourself.
你知道吗，这种分享和分享对我来说并没有比你更好。
You know, this share and share alike doesn't sit any better with me than it does with you.
我和你想的一样。
I'm thinking the same way you are.
这个牧场不够大，容不下我们两个人。
This ranch isn't big enough to hold the two of us.
我们有办法解决这个问题。
There's a way we can settle that.
-杰布，你答应过我不会惹麻烦的-我想听听他要说什么。
- Jeb, you promised me there be no trouble. - I want to hear what he has to say.
-我们怎么解决?-我买断你的股份。
- How can we settle it? - I'll buy you out.
-如果我不想卖呢?-那你就买下我的股份
- Suppose I don't want to sell? - Then you buy me out.
-现在你知道我做不到-亚当请…杰布，什么都别说了你不会为我做那么多吗?
- Now you know I can't do that. - Adam please... Jeb, don't say anything more. Won't you do that much for me?
托尔，你别插手。
Thor, you keep out of this.
如果你不喜欢我的想法，那你有什么想法?
Well, what's your notion, if you don't like mine?
我上战场的时候，我们用掷硬币来解决。
When I went to war we settled with a toss.
这个我留着，如果适合你我们可以再转一遍。
I kept this, maybe if it suits you we can spin it again.
这次可能会给我带来好运。
There might be some luck in it for me this time.
我会把你的。我的钱和你的钱，一个留，一个走。
I'll toss you. My share against yours, one of us stays, one goes.
哦，你不能，你也不能。这是错误和疯狂的。
Oh, you can't, you either. It's wrong and crazy.
从我们小的时候起，我们就一起在这里，我们三个。
Ever since we were little, we've all been here together, the three of us.
这是无法改变的，如果它要被改变。
This is no way to change it if it's going to be changed.
一扔。
One toss.
-你想解释一下吗?-亚当，我求求你和杰布，别这么做
- You want to spin it? - Adam, I beg you and you Jeb, don't do it.
-赢家通吃。——一扔。
- Winner take all. - One toss.
——调用它。——头部。
- Call it. - Heads.
我就知道侧手翻会带来厄运。
I might've known that cartwheel was bad luck.
嗯，我会在城里骑马。
Well, I'll be riding in town.
我明天租个钻井平台回来拿我的东西。
I'll hire a rig tomorrow and come back for my things.
不，你不会的，你什么都没有，除了你穿的衣服和这个。
No, you won't, you ain't got no things, Excepting what you're wearing and this.
明天我再来，你跟我走，如果他想阻止我，我就杀了他。
Tomorrow I'm coming back, You're coming with me, if he tries to stop me, I'll kill him.
-妈不会让你这么做的。-也许她不得不这么做。
- Ma will never let you do this. - Maybe she'll have to.
那我早上跟他一起去，等他来了，我就准备好了。
Then I'll go with him in the morning, when he comes, I'll be ready.
你永远不会，如果这意味着要离开牧场的话。
You'd never, not if it meant leaving the ranch.
牧场不是我的一切，不是我的丈夫。
The ranch isn't everything to me, it isn't a husband.
牧场是一个丈夫，你在说疯话。
The ranch be a husband, you're talking crazy.
它是你的妻子，亚当，因为你没有妻子。
It's been a wife to you Adam, because you don't have a wife.
你只有牧场。好吧，我不属于它。
You just have the ranch. Well, I don't belong to it.
你可以把我从你随身带着的那本破烂账本上拿下来了。
You can take me off that dogeared tally book you carry around.
-那你恨我?-我爱你。
- You hate me then? - I love you.
我一直以为我们三个永远不会分开。
I always thought the three of us would never be apart.
三，三，你总是这么说。
Three, three, you're always saying that.
-但他为什么算数?只有你和我。-现在你才是那个说疯话的人。
- But why does he count? It's you and me. - Now you're the one that's talking crazy.
-我想要一个自己的家。-格兰特·卡勒姆认识他，也认识他的人。
- I want a home of my own. - Grant Callum knew him, knew his people too.
让我查格洛里亚塔县的记录。
Told me to look up the records in Glorieta county.
-是吗?-我当然找到了，我发现了一些东西。
- And did you? - Sure I did and I found something.
有一个叫兰德的家庭曾经住在那里，我找到了足够的证据。
A family named Rand did live there once, I found out enough for me.
-我不让你嫁给他的原因-我不管你的理由是什么。
- A reason why I'll never let you marry him. - I don't care what your reason is.
你说得像个后辈。
You're talking like a back fence gossip.
你觉得这种话对我有意义吗?
Do you think that kind of talk means anything to me?
世界上没有什么能改变我的感觉。
Nothing in the world can change the way I feel.
我一直知道你关心他。
I always knew you cared for him.
我从没想过会有这么多。
I guess I never knew how much.
看来我们得把事情解决了。
Looks as if we're going to have to set things right.
你，你会去找他吗?你会骑马进城把他带回来吗?
You, you'll go after him then? You'll ride in town and bring him back?
我会的，我今晚骑马进城。
I'll do it, I'll ride in town tonight.
丁格尔先生，你接受这个人的借据吗?
Mr. Dingle, you accept this man's IOU?
是的，我买了。
Yes, I'll take it.
-现在把他扔出去-是的。
- Now throw him out. - Yeah.
把你的手拿开，好吗?
Keep your hands off me, will you?
杰克怎么了?你现在不收钱了吗?
What's up Jake? You don't take money in here anymore?
你在酒吧的钱都是假的，我留着你开车的时候用。
Any money you put on this bar is counterfeit, I'm saving you for the wheel.
你遇到了一个差点说服你的人吗?
You run into a fella who nearly convinced you?
他试着。
He tried.
我跟亚当掷了两次硬币，两次都输了。
You know, I flipped this dollar twice with Adam, I lost both times.
上次我上战场，这一次，我离开了牧场。
Last time I went to war, this time, I left the ranch.
你离开牧场了?你的意思是?
You left the ranch? You mean that?
也许你玩的是冷牌。
Maybe you played into a cold deck.
我想这是最好的结果。
Well, I guess it's all for the best.
哦，当然，一个人的运气总有一天会改变的。
Oh sure, a man's luck is bound to change sometime.
在我看来你很幸运，难道你不想为这笔钱做点什么吗?
You appear lucky to me, don't you want some action for this dollar?
这是一种纪念品。
It's kind of a keepsake.
好吧，很多人在变化到来之前已经穷到只剩一块钱了。
Well, many a man is been down to his last dollar before the change does come.
我猜你只是想要这美元。
Guess you just want this dollar.
好吧，拿去吧。
Alright, go ahead and take it.
杰布，你赢了。
Hey, Jeb, you won.
-随它去吧。-哦，这个游戏没有太多的角度。
- Let it ride. - Oh no too many angles at this game.
我宁愿打扑克。
I rather play poker.
杰布，你运气不错，为什么不退出呢?
You had a run of good luck Jeb, why don't you pull out?
哦,再一次。
Oh, once more.
哦，兄弟，好运就在你的肩上。
Oh brother, luck sure riding on your shoulder.
-可能会把这里清理干净。-我有预感你要完了
- Probably clean this place out. - Oh, I got a feeling you're through.
我赌1500块你肯定是感觉不太对劲。
Oh, I be about $1,500 here that says you got a wrong feeling.
乔，给我弄个新牌。
Joe, get me a new deck.
嗯…在这里。
Well... There it is.
我告诉你，如果我是你，我会怎么处理那笔钱。
I'll tell you what I'd do with that money if I were you.
-别告诉我，让我猜猜。-哦，我会买这个生意的。
- Don't tell me, let me guess. - Oh, I'd buy into this business.
-我卖给你一部分。-你不是这个意思吧?
- I'll sell you a piece of it. - You don't mean that?
是的,我喜欢。
Yes, I do.
-你知道为什么吗?——为什么?
- You know why? - Why?
因为人们信任你。
Well, because people trust you.
我只是诚实的杰克·丁格尔。
And I'm just honest Jake Dingle.
我可能会接受你的建议。
You know, I might take you up on that.
我不久就会找生意做的。
I'll be looking for a business by and by.
好吧，你好好考虑一下，然后告诉我，你和我，我们会是一个很好的组合。
Well, you think it over and let me know, we'd make a great combination, you and myself.
如果你真的来了…我教你怎么玩牌，不会伤到什么。
And if you do come in... I'll teach you how to handle cards, it don't hurt anything.
——晚安。-晚安，搭档。
- Good night. - Good night partner.
好好保管那笔钱。
And take good care of that money.
当我走在拉雷多的街道上。
As I walked out on the streets of Laredo.
有一天我离开了拉雷多……我看到一个裹着白色亚麻布的打牛机…裹在白色亚麻布里，像粘土一样冰冷。
I walked out on Laredo one day... I spied a cow puncher wrapped up in white linen... Wrapped in white linen as cold as the Clay.
慢慢地打鼓，轻轻地吹笛子。
Beat the drum slowly and play the fife lowly.
当你带着我走的时候，假装死亡的三月。
Play the dead March as you carry me along.
带我去大草原，铺上草皮。
Take me out to the prairie and lay the sod over me.
因为我是一个可怜的牛仔，我知道我做错了。
For I'm a poor cowboy and I know I've done wrong.
把草皮铺在我身上。
And lay the sod over me.
亚当。
Adam.
现在，让我们继续。
Now, let us continue.
我不同意“知识角落”。
I disagree with the learned corner.
我仍然认为我们是一个合法的机构，有适当的任命。
I still maintain we're a legal body, properly impaneled.
坐下，格兰特，这是我的听证会。
Sit down Grant, this is my hearing.
我不需要县检察官来告诉我该怎么做。
I don't need no county prosecutor to tell me how to run it.
此外，既然检察官叫卡勒姆…我不想说他有偏见，因为我是清白的，我是。
Furthermore, since so happens said prosecutor's name is Callum... I wouldn't want to say he's prejudiced because I'm clean -minded, I am.
我有责任维护法律的执行，不管家庭或其他什么。
It's my duty to see the law administered, regardless of family or anything else.
先生们……我从心底发誓，我从来没有像现在这样想辞职。
Gentlemen... I swear from the bottom of my heart I never felt more like quitting my job than right now.
因为我很清楚这个案子会让一个家庭付出什么代价一个悲伤的母亲和姐妹，他们已经失去了一个儿子，一个兄弟…如果我的猜测是对的，可能又会被法律起诉。
Because I well know what this case may cost a family- A sorrowing mother and sister, who have already lost one son, one brother... if my guess is right may lose another to the law.
Callum小姐……在那个晚上，你看到你哥哥和杰布·兰德吵架了吗?
Miss Callum... On the night in question, did you witness a quarrel between your brother and Jeb Rand?
是的,我看到了。
Yes, I did.
你有没有听到被告对亚当发出任何威胁?
And did you hear the accused utter any threat with regard to Adam?
是的。
Yes.
你可以重复你听到的。
You may repeat what you heard.
杰布说他第二天会回来接我…把我带走，然后娶我。
Jeb said he was coming back next day to get me... to take me with him and marry me.
他说如果亚当试图阻止他，他就会杀了他。
He said if Adam tried to stop him, he'd kill him.
也许你们想喝杯茶。
Perhaps you fellas might like a spot of tea.
现在，这是它的大小，这是两个毫无用处的人，他们需要彼此。
Now, here's the size of it, here's two men that had no use want for each other.
这些都已经被证实了但这不是我们来决定的。
All that's been testified but that ain't what we're here to decide.
看来杰布像格兰特说的那样把他干掉了。
It looks like Jeb shot him down like Grant said.
别着急，我是人。
Hold your horses, I'm a ghyn man.
格兰特和杰布的证词，在我看来。
Grant's word against Jeb's, the way I see it.
杰布从来不是杀人犯
Oh, Jeb never was no murderer.
我想双方都有很多疑问。
I figure there's plenty doubt on both sides.
-你说什么?-没人能和卡勒姆相处得好。
- The heck you say. - Nobody can get along with Ad Callum.
让我们做点事吧，我得回家照看我的摊子了。
Well, let's get something done, I got to get home and look after my stall.
闭嘴。
Shut up.
你们看到将军在杰布身上别了枚勋章。
You fellas saw the general pin a medal on Jeb.
啊，他没有布置伏击。
Ah, he weren't decorating no ambusher.
而是一个为国而战的人。
But a man that fought fair and square for his country.
一个在战场上射杀了十几个人的人会……连个机会都不给他就杀了自己的兄弟。
It don't stand to reason that a man that shot down a dozen fellows in battle would... shoot down his own brother without giving him a chance.
如果一定要钻他，他会做得很好。
If he had to drill him, he'd do it right.
如果他做得对，那就不需要杀人…而是合法的战斗。
And if he done it right, then it ain't no killing... but a lawful fight.
在这一带，我们也没那么不开化……一个人要想赢得合法的战斗，必须把自己的脖子套在绞索上。
And hereabouts we ain't so danged uncivilized... a man can't win a lawful fight without getting his neck in a noose for it.
把茶递过来。
Pass the tea.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
卡勒姆太太，你走之前我能跟你说句话吗?
May I speak to you before you go Mrs. Callum?
我知道你不赞同陪审团的裁决，但那是公平的。
I know you don't hold with the verdict of the jury but it was fair.
我从没杀过亚当。
I never murdered Adam.
牧场会缺人手，而且…如果你允许的话，我很乐意再来帮你。
You'll be shorthanded at the ranch and... If you'll permit me, I'd be happy to come back and help you out.
我的提议是最真诚的。
I make this offer most sincerely.
-离我远点杰布·兰德-我知道你对我的感觉，但是…我希望我能及时改变这一切。
- Get away from me Jeb Rand. - I know how you must feel about me but... I was hoping that in time I could change that.
-现在改变已经太晚了。-妈妈，我们走。
- It's too late to change anything. - Mother, let's go.
不，我说了算。
No, I'll have my say.
你可能在里面洗清了嫌疑，但不是在我面前。
You may have cleared yourself in there but not with me.
和我一起走上绞刑架的台阶。
With me you're walking up the gallows steps.
绞架是我造的，绞索是我绑的。
I built that gallows, I tied the noose.
我对你的爱都死了。
All the love I had for you is dead.
离我远点。
Stay out of my sight.
如果你越过我的分割线，我就放狗咬你。
If you cross my section line, I'll set the dogs on you.
这是你的感觉吗?
Is that the way you feel?
你已经表达得很清楚了所以那年秋天我和杰克在一起的时候。
You'd made pretty clear how you felt so that fall I put in with Jake.
当我站在赌桌的另一边时，我发现赌博有多无聊。
Found out how dull gambling could be when I stood on the other side of the table.
有一两次我们得到了关于你的消息。
Once or twice we got some news about you.
说你生病了，说你住在农场，谁也不见。
How you've been sick, how you were living out at the ranch and not seeing anyone.
我一直盼着你进城，但你从来没有来过。
I watched for you to come in town but you never did.
又到了秋天，我才听到年轻的普伦蒂斯……店主的儿子，要带你和你妈妈去舞会。
It was fall again before I heard young Prentice... the storekeeper's son, was taking you and your mother to the dance.
多思你的女儿，多思你的老人。
Do-Si your daughters and do-Si your old men.
朵思走过大厅，和朵思回到家。
Do-Si past the hall and and do-Si back home.
男人的左手和老左手都是右手。
All the man left and the old left hand is right.
见见你的搭档，然后散步吧，着火了，我不在乎。
Meet your partner and promenade it's on fire and I don't care.
把你的妞放在安乐椅上。
And park your gal in an easy chair.
你想要一杯潘趣酒吗?-我很乐意。
- Would you like a glass of punch? - I'd love it.
-失陪一下——谢谢。
- Excuse me a minute. - Thanks.
女士们先生们，下一个是瓦尔苏维亚纳号。
And now ladies and gentlemen, the next will be the Varsouviana.
-我可以有这个荣幸吗?-请走开。
- May I have the pleasure? - Please go away.
最好跳舞，不然别人会看你的。
Better dance or people will look at you.
我宁愿别人看着我也不愿和我讨厌的人跳舞。
I'd rather people look at me than dance with somebody I hate.
你真是个胆小鬼。
What a coward you are.
胆小鬼才不会来这儿跟你跳舞呢。
A coward wouldn't come here to dance with you.
等一下，好了，大家，慢舞跳够了。
Hold it, all right folks, that's enough of our slow dance.
这是一个摇摆你的女人的机会，所以让你的伙伴来一个鸡肉卷。
Here's a chance to swing your ladies, so get your partners for a chicken reel.
-你看到托尔和杰布跳舞了，对吧?——为什么,是的。
- You saw Thor dancing with Jeb, didn't you? - Why, yes.
来吧，儿子，我们来谈谈。
Come on son, let's you and I have a little talk.
现在，他强迫她，杰布·兰德，她最恨的男人，强迫她和他跳舞。
Now, he forced her, Jeb Rand, the man she hates... most in the world, forced her to dance with him.
我在给她拿潘趣酒。
I was getting her some punch.
你今晚要陪她，对吧?
You're escorting her this evening, aren't you?
是的。
Yes.
你能把她带到这里来让她受辱吗?
Would you bring her here so she could be insulted?
不，先生，我不会让这种事发生的。
No sir, I wouldn't let that happen.
但是发生了，你打算怎么做?
But happened, what you going to do about it?
原谅我们的绅士。
Pardon us gentlemen.
卡莱姆先生，这一切都是很久以前的事了，不关我的事。
Mr. Callum, all this started long ago, it isn't my fight.
-那你不是我想的那个人-我会做正确的事。
- Then you're not the man I took you for. - I'll do what's right.
如果你让他侥幸逃脱，她就再也不会跟你说话了。
If you let him get away with it, she never speak to you again.
-是她说的吗?-如果她没有，她也在想。
- Did she say that? - If she didn't, she's thinking it.
她还在想别的事。
And there's something else she's thinking of.
是她哥哥的死
It's the death of her brother.
卡莱姆先生，我不太会用枪。
Mr. Callum sir, I'm not much good with a gun.
也许你会得到一些帮助。
Maybe you'll have some help.
到小巷上去。
Go up to the alley.
如果他是个诚实的车手，你会在里屋找到他，从窗户开枪。
If he's an honest wheel, you'll find him in the back room, shoot through the window.
不，先生，我不能这么做。
No sir, I, I can't do that.
但我会让他向我坦白的。
But I'll make him come out to me.
杰克，怎么了?你找不到舞伴吗?
What's the matter Jake? Couldn't you find any partner?
你找到了一个不该找的，雷神。
You found one you shouldn't have, Thor.
年轻的普伦蒂斯要找你算账。
Young Prentice is coming over after you for it.
-普伦蒂斯?-他正在过来的路上。
- Prentice? - He's on his way over here now.
干掉他，杰布，到前面去。
Get the drop on him Jeb, go on out front.
-先是亚当，现在是普伦蒂斯。-伙计，你得走了。
- First Adam, now Prentice. - Man, you got to get going.
-我不想对他下手，杰克。-你打算怎么做?
- I don't want to get the drop on him Jake. - What are you going to do?
走到小巷里，让自己消失。
Step out in the alley and make myself scarce.
——兰德先生。-你想要什么?
- Mr. Rand. - What do you want?
我来是因为你对索利所做的。
I've come because of what you did to Thorley.
回家吧，普伦蒂斯，我不想伤害你。
Go on home Prentice, I don't want to hurt you.
为自己辩护，兰德先生。
Defend yourself Mr. Rand.
我要是你就不会这么做，格兰特。
I wouldn't try that if I were you Grant.
让他到办公室来。
Let's get him in the office.
我这么做是为了索利。
I, I did it for Thorley.
对不起普伦蒂斯。
I'm sorry Prentice.
就像他们说的，这是自卫，但他是人们恨我的另一个秘密。
It was self defense just as they said, Yet he was one more part of the mystery of people hating me.
现在我看到抬柩者的靴子，灯光闪烁。
Now I saw the boots of the pallbearers, flashes of light.
我有一种失落而又可怕的感觉再次笼罩着我。
And I had that feeling some lost and awful thing come over me again.
我不确定杀死普伦蒂斯是我的错还是因为我内心的邪恶。
I wasn't sure whether killing Prentice was my fault... whether it was due to some badness locked up in me.
但我确信我对你的爱是唯一的希望和唯一的答案。
But I was sure of my love for you, that was the only hope and the only answer.
如果爱能从这一切中产生，我们可能还有一些机会，我们可能会活下去。
If love could come out of all this, we might still have some chance, we might live.
那时候我就知道我必须拥有你。
Right then I knew I had to have you.
我必须爬过2个坟墓才能找到你，但世界上没有什么能阻止我。
I had to climb across 2 graves to get to you but nothing in the world would hold me back.
那是谁来了。
Who's that coming.
杰布兰特。
It's Jeb Rand.
他要来拜访我。
He's coming to call on me.
杰布兰特?呼吁吗?
Jeb Rand? Calling on you?
我知道他会来，我一直在等他。
I knew he'd come, I've been expecting him.
你没有权利指望他，更不用说去见他了。
You've no right to expect him, much less to see him.
我要请他进来。
I'm asking him in.
对不起，让你久等了，请进来好吗?
Sorry to have kept you waiting, won't you come in?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你能接待我真是太好了。
Was kind of you to receive me.
-请坐。——谢谢。
- Please sit down. - Thank you.
-来点咖啡好吗?-我不想给你添麻烦。
- Won't you like some coffee? - I don't want to put you to any trouble.
哦，不麻烦，我们正准备吃点。
Oh, it's no trouble, we were just going to have some.
很抱歉，我们没有其他的了。
I'm sorry we have nothing else to offer.
在这个家里，我们只有一点酒。
In this house all we have is a little wine.
那只是圣诞节和节假日的。
That's just for Christmas and holidays.
我好像想起了那瓶酒。
Seems to me I remember something about that wine.
那是妈妈从圣达菲寄来的音乐盒。
That's a music box Ma had sent from Santa Fe.
“我知道，”伦敦德里航空公司说。
I know, plays the Londonderry Air.
一首老调，有些人不喜欢。
An old fashioned tune, some people don't care for it.
我可以抽烟吗?你会介意吗?-不，当然不是
- May I smoke or would that annoy you? - No, of course not.
这是我做的样品，我不太擅长。
This is a sampler I'm making, I'm not very good at it.
我们在恋爱呢，就像你很久以前要求我的那样。
Here we are courting, the way you asked me to long ago.
但这是完全不同的。你坐在那儿，我抽烟，你做针线活。
But it's all different. You sitting there, me smoking, you sewing.
就像任何普通人一样，这比在街上打架或大喊大叫更糟糕。
Just like any ordinary people, it's worse than fighting or yelling in the street.
-你不想喝咖啡吗?——不,谢谢。
- Don't you want your coffee? - No, thanks.
也许以后。你为什么不坐在这张舒服的椅子上呢?
Perhaps later. Why don't you sit down in the comfortable chair?
公司总是用这个。
Company always uses that one.
我想知道你在跟我玩什么疯狂的游戏，但我做不到但我知道我会跟你玩到底。
I tried to figure out what crazy game you were playing with me, And I couldn't but I knew I'd play it out with you right to the end.
-我看到什么了吗?-我宣布。
- Am I seeing things? - Well, I declare.
晚安，杰布，明天见?——当然。
Good night Jeb - I'll see you tomorrow? - Of course.
托尔。
Thor.
托尔,到这里来。
Thor, come here.
-这是什么?——更接近。
- What is it? - Come closer.
把灯打开。
Turn the lamp up.
-没错，我想看看你。-我没有改变妈妈。
- That's right, I want to look at you. - I haven't changed mother.
我教过你什么?这让你知道怎么给我们丢脸。
What have I taught you? That showed you how to bring dishonor on us.
我没有给你带来耻辱。
I've brought you no dishonor.
杰布今晚给我的我要嫁给他妈妈。
Jeb gave me this tonight. I'm going to marry him mother.
这里面有什么我不明白的?
What's in this that I don't understand?
-那你爱他吗?-我只有一个想法。
- Do you love him then? - I've only one thought.
我生命中的每一分钟，都在诉说我有多恨他。
Every minute of my life, how much I hate him.
但你戴着他的戒指。
But you wear his ring.
如果我是男人，我早就杀了他。
If I were a man, I would've killed him long ago.
亚当死后。然后他杀了普伦蒂斯，来追求我。
After Adam's death. Then he killed Prentice and came courting me.
突然间，杀戮是不够的，我需要更多。
All of a sudden killing wasn't enough, I had to have more.
更要用尽我心中所有的恨。
Much more, to use up all the hate I have in me.
托尔，我要卖掉这里，我要离开。我不会待在这里看着这一切发生。
Thor, I'll sell this place, I'll go away. I won't stay here and see this thing happen.
也许那是最好的。
Perhaps that may be best.
你离开一段时间，我们很快就会在一起。
You go away for a while, we'll be together again soon.
没有哪个女人能完成你的计划。
No woman ever lived who could go through with what you're planning.
除了我没有别的女人，因为我花了一辈子的时间才教会我他是什么。
No woman but me, because it's taken all my life to teach me what he is.
他给我们带来耻辱和悲伤。现在他想让我榨干最后一滴。
He put shame and grief on us... and now he'd like to squeeze out the last drop of it by having me.
他想要我，我就嫁给他。
He wants me and I'll marry him.
当他认为他抓住了我，他就会失去一切。
That moment when he thinks he has me, he'll lose everything.
因为那时我就会杀了他。
Because that's when I'm going to kill him.
-无论贫富。-无论贫富。
- For richer, for poorer. - For richer, for poorer.
-无论疾病或健康-无论疾病或健康
- In sickness and in health. - In sickness and in health.
-直到死亡将我们分开-直到死亡将我们分开
- Until death do us part. - Until death do us part.
你为什么那样做?
What made you do that?
我不知道，这么好的年轻人却没人参加婚礼。
I don't know, such fine young folks and nobody at the wedding.
给你个惊喜，我给你买了栋房子。
Have a surprise for you, I bought you a house.
好了查理。
Alright Charlie.
现在你也看到了，所以我才叫你来。
Well, now you've seen it, that's why I sent for you.
既然我们都是卡莱姆斯，我就不用告诉你我们要怎么做了。
Being as we're all Callums here, I don't have to tell you what we going to do about it.
当然，你会给自己和我们都带来麻烦的。
Sure enough, you'll get yourself in trouble and us too.
是啊，自从格兰特诞生以来，时代变了。
Yeah, times have changed since all this started Grant.
-你不能再凌驾于法律之上了。-你在跟我说法律吗?
- You can't ride herd on the law no more. - You telling me about the law?
不,先生。
No sir.
你跟他想的一样，不去吗?
You thinking like him, that you're not going?
没错。
That's right.
我想我们都要去。
I think we're all going.
当我听说要拍卖的时候我…我觉得买下来总比看着它传给陌生人好。
When I heard about the auction I... figured it'd be better for me to buy it than see it pass on to strangers.
请允许我。
Allow me.
我知道背着新娘进来是一种习俗，但也许我们可以不计较。
I know it's a custom to carry the bride in but perhaps we can let that go.
我一直以为我结婚后会有所有的装饰品。
I always figured when I got married that I'd have all the trimmings.
你可能注意到了一些变化，我从堪萨斯城带来了一些配菜。
You may notice some changes, there some fixings I brought here from Kansas City.
你这地方真漂亮。
Mighty pretty place you got here.
查理，你能把兰德太太的包拿到前卧室去吗?
Charlie, would you take Mrs. Rand's bags into the front bedroom please?
我一定会的。
I sure will.
进来。
Come in.
-你很漂亮。——谢谢。
- You're very beautiful. - Thank you.
我希望你在这里过得舒服。
I hope you'll be comfortable here.
在这所房子里，不需要什么就能使我感到舒适。
In this house it takes very little to make me comfortable.
给你拿了些酒。
Brought you some wine.
我想这是习俗，为新娘的健康干杯。
It's customary, I believe, to drink to a bride's health.
你很勇敢的。
You're very gallant.
-所以你知道。-你和我很像。
- So you know. - You and I are much alike.
有时我能读懂你的想法。
There times when I can read your thoughts.
问问自己如果我处在你的位置会怎么做。
By asking myself what I'd do if I were in your place.
我知道这是一个让人恼火的丈夫的品质…但这可能会让事情对你来说更容易些。
I know that's an irritating quality in a husband... but it may help to make things easier for you.
-别再靠近了。-你确定这样可以吗?
- Don't come any closer. - You sure this is all right?
普伦蒂斯错过了，因为光线不好亚当太着急了。
Prentice missed because the light was bad Adam was too anxious.
我很高兴你没有那些残疾。
I'm glad you don't suffer from those handicaps.
不,我不喜欢。
No, I don't.
你知道你为什么想我吗?
You know why you missed me?
因为我恨你恨得手发抖。
Because I hate you so my hand shook.
你的手颤抖了，但不是因为你恨我。
Your hand shook but not because you hate me.
把枪放下，托尔
Put the gun down Thor.
杰布，抱着我。抱着我。
Oh Jeb, hold me. Hold me.
——杰布?它是什么?有什么事吗?-我得走了。
- Jeb? What is it? What's the matter? - Got to leave here.
外面的人，他们想杀我，都是格兰特·卡勒姆干的。
There men outside, they want to kill me, it's all Grant Callum's doing.
我不知道为什么，但从我记事起他就想让我死。
I don't know why but he's wanted me dead ever since I can remember.
哦，带我一起走吧。
Oh, take me with you.
我不能，但我们可以在一起一段时间。
I can't but we can be together in a little while.
熊掌堡那边有个废弃的老农场，在那等我。
There's an old ruined ranch up by Bear Paw Butte, meet me there.
我怎么找到它?
How do I find it?
沿着这条小路穿过Rimrock峡谷，穿过县界。
Take the trail through Rimrock Canyon, across the county line.
哦，我会去的。
Oh, I'll be there.
看起来他是直接从悬崖上跳下去的。
Looks like he jumped clean off this bluff here.
-他跑得比我们快-我们放弃吧
- Ah, he just outrun us. - Let's give it up.
我有预感，我知道他在哪。
I got a hunch I know where he is.
拉斯，去找卡勒姆妈妈，把她带到熊掌山庄。
Russ, go fetch Ma Callum and bring her to Bear Paw Butte.
这一切还会再次发生，但我现在不在乎。
It's all going to happen again but I don't care now.
我知道我一直在寻找一个重要的答案，我为什么会孤独?
I know there's one big answer I've always looked for, why I was alone?
为什么所有事情都出错了?为什么我恨而不是爱?
Why everything went wrong? Why I had hate in me instead of love?
我和你背上都骑着一条黑狗。
Was a black dog riding my back and yours too.
我想我们失去了机会，但现在我们也无能为力了。
I guess we lost our chance but there's nothing we can do about it now.
但有办法，我们得离开这里，我们两个。
Oh but there is, we got to get away from here, both of us.
杰布·兰德我们知道你在里面快出来
Jeb Rand, we know you're in there, come on out.
我们给你两分钟时间。
We'll give you two minutes.
你疼吗?
Are you hurt?
我现在想起来了，那些我从小就做的梦。
I remember now, those dreams I've been having ever since I was a kid.
闪光是枪声，开枪的人是我父亲。
The flashes were gunfire and the man shooting was my father.
我妹妹躺在地板上死了，我的兄弟们也死了。
My sister lay on the floor dead, and my brothers were dead too.
靴子和马刺，都是我父亲的。
The boots and spurs, they were my father's.
然后他被击中，我看到他摔倒，我知道他被杀了。
Then was hit, I saw him fall, I knew he'd been killed.
我太害怕了，不敢喊，就呆在那里。
I was too scared to yell so I just stayed there.
然后一个男人进来了，格兰特·卡勒姆。
Then a man came in, Grant Callum.
拖着一个女人，她是你的母亲。
Was dragging a woman with him, she was your mother.
他让她现在看看她的兰德。
He told her to look at her Rand now.
我记得那些话，你的兰德。
I remember those words, your Rand.
他问她，她对他的爱是否值得她所做的一切。
He asked her if the love she had for him was worth what she'd done.
然后他把她推倒，把我父亲拖了出来。
Then he threw her down and dragged my father out.
杰布，亲爱的，太可怕了。
Jeb darling, how horrible.
-一定是我妈妈…——等等。
- Must mean that my mother... - One minute.
-出来，不然我们就把你拖出来。- - - - - -来吧。
- Come out or we'll come and drag you out. - Come on.
我不会的，你这么做是为了我因为你怕我会受伤。
I won't, you're doing this for me because you're afraid I'll be hurt.
我不想没有你的生活，我们要战斗。
I don't want to live without you, we got to fight.
我们出来，别开枪。
We coming out, don't shoot.
把你的枪扔出去。
Throw your gun out.
举起手来。
Put your hands up.
我让他跟你打，如果有必要，就死在战斗中。
Oh, I told him to fight you, to die fighting if he had to.
让我走。
Let me go.
妈妈，你不会让他们这么做的。
Oh mother, you won't let them do this.
格兰特，你终于如愿以偿了。
So Grant, you going to have it your way at last.
我告诉过你我会等他长大。
I told you I'd wait until he was grown.
现在他长大了，他得到了他的遗产，只是这是他做的。
Well, now he's growed and he gets his legacy, only it's made out of him.
他赢得了这一切，就像他父亲赢得了领先一样。
He earned it just as his father earned the lead he got.
他偷了我哥哥的妻子。
When he stole my brother's wife.
那就是杰布的父亲，你爱他。
Then it was Jeb's father, you loved him.
是的，只是她忘了她嫁给了卡莱姆。
Yes, only she forgot she was married to a Callum.
牵匹马过来，给我拿根绳子。
Bring a horse here, get me a rope.
杰布跟我说了你们的恩怨
Jeb told me about the feud.
现在我明白了我不知道的部分，这一切都是因为你的爱，你的内疚。
Now I understand the part I didn't know, it all started because of your love, your guilt.
所以你才想看杰布被绞死。
That's why you'd like to see Jeb hanged.
你不知道你在说什么，这不是我的要求。
You don't know what you saying, this is none of my asking.
你从来没有给杰布机会，你从来没有告诉他真相让他保护自己。
You never gave Jeb a chance, you never told him the truth so he could protect himself.
-我只是想保护你-你撒谎。
- I was trying to protect you. - That's a lie.
-你感到羞耻。-我已经为我的所作所为付出了代价。
- You were ashamed. - I've paid for what I did.
我给了他一个家，我收留了他。
I gave the boy a home, I took him in.
为所有的杀戮买单?因为我父亲和杰布的父亲的死?
That paid for all the killings? For the way my father died and Jeb's father?
其实不是，你爱他的父亲。
Well, it didn't, you loved his father.
还是你现在回想起你曾经爱过的事而感到羞愧?
Or are you ashamed now to remember how you loved?
不，我爱他的父亲。
No, I loved his father.
你辜负了他，母亲，也辜负了你自己。
You failed him mother and you failed yourself.
你失去了你爱的人，他死在这里。
You lost the man you loved, he died here.
但我的人不会，除非他们把我也杀了。
But my man won't, unless they kill me too.
你不能。
You can't.
杰布，对不起，我对你做了那么多错事。
I'm sorry Jeb, for all the wrong I did you.
原谅我。
Forgive me.
你不用问我这个，你已经把我的生活还给我了。
You didn't have to ask me that, you've given me back my life.
——哦,妈妈。-我告诉过你，杰布，不要回头。
- Oh, mother. - I told you once Jeb, never to look back.
向前看，我现在再告诉你一遍。
Look ahead, I tell you that again now.
那时我不能，但现在我可以，而且愿意。
I couldn't then but now I can and will.
带你妻子回家，杰布。
Take your wife home Jeb.